<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-06T16:39:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">How to Execute</title><subtitle>Execution is the game. Here's how to play the damn game.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Money, Money, Raise Money!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/02/raising-money.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Money, Money, Raise Money!" /><published>2016-11-02T10:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T10:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/02/raising-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/02/raising-money.html">&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to know about raising money is that &lt;strong&gt;you should try not to raise money.&lt;/strong&gt; It makes everything a lot more complex and you also have more pressure on yourself. If you have the opportunity to build a business and fuel your growth without giving away equity, TAKE IT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you need to raise money, make it a priority and get it done as quickly as possible. It is a big source of distraction and it is time-consuming. First, assign one and only one person to the task. Second, &lt;strong&gt;try to schedule all your meetings in the shortest time span possible.&lt;/strong&gt; Here is a trick from &quot;How to start a startup&quot;, tell everyone you want a meeting in two or three weeks because you have a truckload of things to take care of for a new release or something. They are more likely to have openings in their schedule and you look like you don't really need their money. This will help you reduce the time spent on this task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tough part is usually to get meetings with investors and for that, there are no magic tricks. Go out and meet people. You are &lt;strong&gt;looking for someone who can introduce you to his own investors&lt;/strong&gt; or if you have past investors use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider is that you are going to ask them money. Technically, they are in a position of power. You should be looking for ways to reverse that. The word on the street is that the best way to raise money is to make your business better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't wait until you need money to create relationships with investors.&lt;/strong&gt; You should call for a meeting just to tell them where we are now and where we will be in 2 months or 3 months. You need to show them that you are getting traction and that you are doing what it takes to succeed. That's obviously easier to do if you already have relations with investors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much money should be raised? This is also a tricky one because there are a few elements to consider. When you are raising, too much money is as bad as not enough. If you raise too much capital, you will probably end up giving too much equity or your valuation will be too high. If you don't raise enough capital, you may not be able to reach your milestone making it difficult to raise another round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, you need to figure out &lt;strong&gt;how much money you need in the bank to achieve the next big milestone &lt;/strong&gt;of your company. It is time to use your spreadsheet skills. How much time do you need to achieve the milestone and how much are you going to spend during those months? You can use your current burn rate and how much you expect it to grow to figure this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the money, don't go crazy. It is easy to spend all this money the wrong way. Instead, you should increase your burn rate progressively. A new employee the first month, increase the marketing budget the next month, get a bigger office the month after, etc. &lt;strong&gt;Running out of cash is the number one reason of failure at venture-backed startups.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The first thing you need to know about raising money is that you should try not to raise money. It makes everything a lot more complex and you also have more pressure on yourself. If you have the opportunity to build a business and fuel your growth without giving away equity, TAKE IT.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a kickass Team.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/02/building-a-kickass-team.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a kickass Team." /><published>2016-11-02T10:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T10:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/02/building-a-kickass-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/02/building-a-kickass-team.html">&lt;p&gt;I am assuming that you have your founding members, you have built part of your product and you hopefully have a little traction at this point. This is awesome! Now, you are like we need to hire ASAP because we need help. Wait for a second mate... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be the first time in your whole life that you get to choose the people you are going to work with. You should be excited AF. However, you should stop right there and think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I really need an employee? Can I keep going a few more weeks without bringing someone in? You may also want to consider if you are going to need someone for the next years or only for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring someone means that you are going to increase the burn rate and you are going to slow your decision-making process. You may not notice it right away, but after 3, 4, 5 you are gonna start noticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire only if you have a desperate need to.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so now you desperately need an employee and you want to hire him yesterday. If that's the case, then you should have started branding yourself as an awesome employer a while back. This is important because it is going to attract the best talents out there. This can make a big difference if you are trying to poach people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start your employer branding before you start recruiting.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first couple of employees should be smart people and not only doers. You want to hire smart people because they will be able to adapt and make good decisions. It means you don't have to put in place a shit load of procedure for anything. You give them the basic of the structure and they will do what needs to be done. This way you also avoid micro-managing everyone and you can focus on your priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire the smartest people&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not mean you should not take care of them. As a hiring manager, it is part of your role to give constant feedback to everyone. This is an important aspect of onboarding a new team member and it has a big impact on the performance as well as retention. You should not wait three months before you sit with your team to give them feedback. Do it on a regular basis and you will see an enormous difference in the performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give feedback quickly and constantly.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should always keep your ears open and listen to the feedback they have to give you. They can also help you to become better at managing your team. At the end of the day, the team should help everyone improve and be better every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to your team’s feedback.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad part about all this... sometimes you still need to fire someone. Do it quickly to avoid collateral damage. We all do some mistakes, but the difference between winning and losing is how quickly you admit it and fix it. A bad hire can literally kill the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire swiftly and move on!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I am assuming that you have your founding members, you have built part of your product and you hopefully have a little traction at this point. This is awesome! Now, you are like we need to hire ASAP because we need help. Wait for a second mate...</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What are the main areas of execution to get right?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/01/area-of-execution.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are the main areas of execution to get right?" /><published>2016-11-01T10:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T10:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/01/area-of-execution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/11/01/area-of-execution.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team, Product &amp;amp; Growth!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a little bit more complicated than &quot;get this right and you will succeed&quot;, but these three things are crucial. Team, product, and growth are the three variables you can control on a day-to-day basis and you must pay very good attention to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The priority changes depending on your business stage and that is up to you to figure it out. Plus, you need to keep your eyes on the ball while watching the other two. That's why execution is so hard. You need all three to succeed, if only one of the three goes south, you are screwed! As a starting point, I think you should tackle everything in this specific order&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your team is the first thing you should focus on. You need to make sure you surround yourself with the best people from day 1. You would rather have an A-team with a B-product than a B-team with an A-product. A great team can turn a business around when the product sucks but a great product won't save a bad team during tough days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a team is a critical part of your execution. From the founding members to your first employees, you need to hire awesome people. By awesome I mean, smart and fun to work with. I don't want to scare the shit out of you, but a bad decision can cost you your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A- You want to be surrounded by people who are equally smart at the very least or smarter.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;B- You want everyone to have the same vision, values, motivation and passion for what you are building.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;C- You want a complementary and multidisciplinary team.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;D- You want someone you will enjoy spending your life with. You're in for a hell of a ride!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Product&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are gonna be selling this, so you better be god damn proud of it. However, you need to balance high quality and speed of delivery. You need to understand that sometimes it is better to ship a not-so-perfect product quickly than a perfect product too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing a successful product remains something pretty hard even nowadays. A lot of products fail every day and every year. While some people have the ability to develop products with intuition, most of us need to rely on real data. It doesn't mean your intuition should be left out, but you need to balance that with validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will dramatically increase the success of your product if... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You are solving a meaningful problem for your users.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You listen to what your users has to say about what you've built so far.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You develop the features you are sick of hearing about. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won't wake up tomorrow with half a million users. You need to test channels, measure results and figure out what makes sense for your product. This is never ending trial and error because your channel today may not be working tomorrow. Don't dismiss channels because you think they don't work or because your competitors don't use them. In fact, you should use the channels your competitors as dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/swlh/the-19-channels-you-can-use-to-get-traction-93c762d19339#.suid4h632&quot;&gt;19 channels of acquisiton&lt;/a&gt; proposed by the book &quot;Traction&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Targeting blogs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Publicity&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Search engine marketing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Unconventional PR&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Search engine optimization&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Social and display ads&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Offline ads&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Content marketing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Email marketing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Viral marketing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Engineering as marketing&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Business Development&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Affiliate programs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Existing platforms&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Trade shows&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Offline events&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Speaking engagements&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Community building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don't want to spend too much money on acquisition if you have a leaking bucket at the other end. By leaking bucket I mean a product that has a bad retention. Every product has a breaking point where your retention is too bad to continue growing. This will happen regardless of the amount of money spent because at one point you either don't have enough money to sustain or you can't acquire more users.The best and least expensive way to grow remains to increase your retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team + Product + Growth ≠ 100% chance of success.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;However, you are making damn sure you are on the right track.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Team, Product &amp;amp; Growth!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Execution is the Game.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/31/execution-is-the-game.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Execution is the Game." /><published>2016-10-31T10:57:54-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-31T10:57:54-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/31/execution-is-the-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/31/execution-is-the-game.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you heard that line before? &quot;An idea is worth nothing without execution&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't think I have ever met someone willing to challenge that. You may have a great idea, but if you can't execute.. well you are not going anywhere pal. On the other end, you may have a very ordinary idea combined with a laser-focused execution and you will succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Execution is - indeed - the game. It is 99% execution and the tiny 1% leftover is your idea. (the percentage is arguable, the outcome of a great execution is not)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is execution?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Execution is all about doing. It is all the things you do in your day-to-day to achieve your business goals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why execution is such a deal breaker?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two critical aspects strategy and execution. You need to know what to do and then you need to do it right. Your execution doesn't have to be perfect. However, the more things you get right, the higher are your chance of success. The landscape is always changing and you need to adapt your execution. Some people have the knowledge of what needs to be done, but they can't maintain enough focus to do it and for other people, it is the complete opposite. Whether you are working alone or as a team, you need focus and commitment to figure out what to do and then do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is pretending anything here, but there are some key principles that can lead you a long way when it comes to execution for your startup. At the end of the day, execution will make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is how to play the damn game!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Have you heard that line before? &quot;An idea is worth nothing without execution&quot;</summary></entry></feed>
